welcome to your very first tutorial on
ยินดีต้อนรับสู่บทแนะนำแรก ๆ ของคุณ
beginning HTML. HTML is the bedrock of
เริ่ม HTML HTML เป็นข้อมูลพื้นฐานของ
the world wide web and if you're going
เวิลด์ไวด์เว็บและถ้าคุณกำลังจะไป
to do anything even in other languages
ทำทุกอย่างแม้ในภาษาอื่น ๆ
involving the web it is highly important
ที่เกี่ยวข้องกับเว็บเป็นสิ่งสำคัญมาก
you know HTML so let's take a look at
คุณรู้จัก HTML แล้วลองมาดูกันดีกว่า
some of these bullet points and again
บางส่วนของสัญลักษณ์เหล่านี้และอีกครั้ง
this is an introductory video in the
นี่เป็นวิดีโอแนะนำใน
next video we'll actually start doing
วิดีโอถัดไปที่เราจะเริ่มทำจริง
some code now as you can see in that
โค้ดบางตัวตอนนี้ดูได้จากที่นี่
first bullet point HTML stands for
ครื่องหมายลูกศรแรก HTML ย่อมาจาก
hypertext markup language and you might
ภาษามาร์คอัปพาดหัวและคุณอาจ
say wow what is that but it's actually
ว้าวสิ่งที่เป็น แต่ที่จริง
very easy to use HTML. HTML is a document
ง่ายมากที่จะใช้ HTML HTML เป็นเอกสาร
that contains text that's it it's very
ที่มีข้อความอยู่มาก
easy to read so it's not like Java which
ง่ายต่อการอ่านจึงไม่เหมือน Java ซึ่ง
kind of reads like hieroglyphics hTML is
ชนิดของการอ่านเช่น hieroglyphics hTML คือ
just a document that contains text so
เพียงแค่เอกสารที่มีข้อความเป็นเช่นนั้น
it's similar to like Microsoft Word or
มันคล้ายกับ Microsoft Word หรือ
even notepad or WordPad so again it's
แม้แต่ Notepad หรือ WordPad อีกต่อไป
very easy to read now once you've
ง่ายมากที่จะอ่านตอนนี้เมื่อคุณได้
created your HTML document web browsers
สร้างเว็บเบราเซอร์เอกสาร HTML ของคุณแล้ว
can read and display documents that
สามารถอ่านและแสดงเอกสารได้